A Guide to the Papers of Everett Parker Lesley, Jr.
Old Dominion University
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library,, Old Dominion University
Papers of Everett Parker Lesley, Jr. 1907-1982
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library,, Old Dominion University
RG17-2B1
9 Hollinger Document Cases, 3.75 linear feet.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Open to researchers without restriction.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Mark Lesley on November 18, 1982.
Biographical/Historical Information
Everett Parker Lesley, Jr., known as Parker Lesley, was born in Baltimore, Maryland on August 31, 1913. He graduated from Palo Alto Union High School, California, in 1930 and proceeded to attend Stanford University and graduated with a Bachelor of Arts Degree, Classical Literature (Greek), in 1934. From 1935 to 1938 he was a Scholar Fellow and an Advanced Fellow in Art and Archaeology at Princeton University. In 1935 he earned a Certificat des études, Institut d'Art et d'Archéologie from the University of Paris; in 1937 he earned a Master of Fine Arts, Art and Archaeology, Princeton University. Also in 1937 as a Belgian- American Educational Foundation Fellow he earned a Certificat des études from the University of Brussels, Belgium.
Lesley enlisted as Private in the United States Army, June 1942 and progressed through the grades to Sergeant. He was commissioned December 1942 at the Quartermaster Corps Officer Candidate School and progressed through the ranks to Major. He was discharged from the U. S. Army December 1946. During his military career he was awarded a Bronze Star for Meritorious Service, Army Commendation Medal, Chevalier of the Order of Polonia Restituta (Poland) and Honor Medal in Silver for Art and Science of the House-Order of Orange-Nassau (The Netherlands).
In 1942 Lesley married Miriam Pfaff Lucker and the two were divorced in 1948.
Lesley was Curator of European Art at Detroit Institute of Arts in 1938. From 1939 to 1942 he was Assistant Professor of Art and Architecture at University of Minnesota. He served in the U. S. Army from 1942 to 1946. The following year he was Chief of the Restitution Division with the Office of Military Government for Greater Hesse (Germany). From 1950 to 1954 as Assistant Keeper he progressed to Associate Keeper and then to Keeper of Department of Exhibitions at The Cooper Union (NYC). In 1955 he was contracted by Fortune Magazine, which resulted in two published articles. 1955 to 1958 he was self-employed in New York cataloguing private collections. He moved to Norfolk, Virginia in 1959 and became the Norfolk Museum's Acting Director. Also in 1959 he was appointed Assistant Professor of Art at the College of William and Mary in Norfolk and taught under that title up to 1967 (in 1963 the College became Old Dominion College). He began building up the Art Department during 1960 to 1964. From 1968 to 1969 he was titled Professor of Art and was co-chairman of the Art Department (in 1969 Old Dominion College became Old Dominion University). Throughout the remainder of his tenure Lesley did not hold the position of chairman, he continued to teach as Professor of Art until his retirement in 1979 as Eminent Professor; between 1970 through 1979 he went on leave two times: 1972-1973; and 1975-1976.
Lesley was fairly fluent in the German language, fluent reading knowledge in French, working knowledge in Italian and Spanish, studied Hebrew and had a fluent knowledge of classical Greek and Latin. His teaching specialties were Classic and Byzantine Art, Medieval Art, European Painting from the 17th Century to the present (1982), American Painting, History of Architecture and Architectural Design and History of the Decorative Arts.
Lesley authored articles in "The Art Bulletin", "Bulletin of the Detroit Institute of Arts", "Art in America", and "The Art Journal"; in 1945, a Report of The General Board, European Theater of Operations, War Department, "Monuments, Fine Arts and Archives Operations in the European Theater"; at The Cooper Union Museum, 1950-1954, "Leather", "Alter Ego", "Lacquer", "Conspicuous Waist", "Enamel" and "The Prince Regent's Style"; December 1955 and January 1956 (with Eric Hodgins), Fortune Magazine, "The Great International Art Market"; catalogue of the Lillian Thomas Pratt Collection of Russian Imperial Jewels, The Virginia Museum of Fine Arts; Art-historical handbook (2nd version), Norfolk Museum of Arts and Sciences; "The Iconography of the Spirit"; "Bibelots"; and a book "Renaissance Jewels and Jeweled Objects", The Baltimore Museum of Art, 1968.
During Lesley's teaching years he ventured on many trips across the world; England, Israel, the Netherlands and Turkey. After his retirement from Old Dominion University he traveled to California and Washington state, U.S.A., India, Nepal, Russia, Taiwan and Thailand.
Everett Parker Lesley, Jr. died Saturday, February 13, 1982 in his home.
Scope and Content
The Papers of E. Parker Lesley, Jr., dating from 1907 to 1982, contains personal documents, student records, military records, correspondence, travel information, printed materials, photo-slides, photographs, negatives, artifacts and miscellaneous documents. The bulk of the collection documents his professional knowledge pertaining to art history.
Arrangement
This collection is broken down into the following series: I. Personal Documents; II. Student Records; III. Military Records; IV. Correspondence; V. Travel; VI. Printed Materials; VII. Photo Slides; VIII. Photographs; IX. Negatives; X. Artifacts; and XI. Miscellaneous.
Series I: Personal Documents. This series is divided into five sub-series of personal documents. Sub-series A: Calendar Planner; B: Pocket Notepad; C: Travel Log; D: Works and E: Miscellaneous.
Sub-series A: Calendar Planner. Includes three calendar planners from various years dated from 1974 to 1981.
Sub-series B: Pocket Notepad. Includes six notepads from various dates from June 1977 to October 1979.
Sub-series C: Travel Log. Includes one travel log from Norfolk to Iowa dated from August to September 1962.
Sub-series D: Works. Includes works composed by Lesley. Of interest are works pertaining to art-historical handbook, "Bibelots" manuscript, lecture notes and "Iconography of the Spirit".
Sub-series E: Miscellaneous. Includes documents dated from April 1914 to January 1982. Documents his date of birth, baptism, divorce and one porcelain picture his ex-wife Miriam Pfaff-Lesley. Also of interest is a German to English poetry translation.
Series II: Student Records. Includes Lesley's student records dated from 1930 to 1947. Documents his high school diploma, Bachelor of Arts Degree, and Master of Fine Arts. Also of interest are transcripts, a degree, a certificate and a letter of award.
Series III: Military Records. Includes an Award of the Bronze Star Medal Citation; certificates of commendation, completion, proficiency, promotion and service; and two Honorable Discharges: one from Quartermaster Corps Officer Candidate School (QMC OCS) and one from U.S. Army.
Series IV: Correspondence. This series is divided into seven sub-series of correspondence. Sub-series A: Amsterdam trip; B: Brenda Gilchrist; C: John V. Lesley; D: Riemann Family; E: John Roper; F: Steven Rustari; and G: Miscellaneous.
Sub-series A: Amsterdam trip. Includes correspondence with the Private Secretary to Her Majesty the Queen of Netherlands regarding Class: Art 320D.
Sub-series B: Brenda Gilchrist. Includes correspondence with Brenda Gilchrist regarding the completion of Lesley's manuscript "Bibelots".
Sub-series C: John V. Lesley. Includes almost eleven years of correspondence with Lesley's brother John (a.k.a. Jack). John refers to E. Parker as "Bill".
Sub-series D: Riemann Family. Includes correspondence with the Riemann Family (Lesley is the godfather of the eldest son Christopher Riemann). Of interest is the correspondence between Lesley and Christopher Riemann. Also includes photographs directly related to the correspondence.
Sub-series E: John Roper. Includes correspondence between Lesley (a.k.a. Sambo) and John Roper (a.k.a. Jack).
Sub-series F: Steven Rustari. Includes almost eight years of correspondence with Steven Rustari.
Sub-series G: Miscellaneous. Includes a wide range of correspondence with as many people. Of interest is the correspondence between E. Parker, Jr. and E. Parker, Sr.
Series V: Trips. This series is divided into five sub-series of trips. Sub-series A: California, U.S.A.; B: Russia; C: Seattle, WA, U.S.A.; D: Taiwan, Thailand, India & Nepal; and E: Turkey.
Sub-series A: California, U.S.A. Includes a brochure, postcards, maps and miscellaneous documents. Of interest is a "5,000 Years of Korean Art" brochure from the Asian Art Museum of San Francisco.
Sub-series B: Russia. Includes one map, various travel documents, correspondence from Mayree Fourman (includes photographs), various hotel documents, theater reviews (in Russian) and miscellaneous documents.
Sub-series C: Seattle, Washington, U.S.A. This trip tour was centralized around the Pacific Northwest (Richard) Wagner Festival featuring the complete cycle of Der Ring des Nibelungen (The Ring of the Nibelung). Includes maps, various documents pertaining to Der Ring, a newspaper review of Der Ring, a tour group photograph and miscellaneous documents. Of interest is the Pacific Northwest Wagner Festival program.
Sub-series D: Taiwan, Thailand, India & Nepal. Includes printed documents of Bali, Nepal, Taiwan, Thailand and literature from Taiwan's National Palace Museum. Also includes a travel log, photographs, various travel documents and miscellaneous documents. Of interest is the literature from Taiwan's National Palace Museum.
Sub-series E: Turkey. Includes a class roster, a syllabus, site information and correspondence with Lesley's nephew, Mark Lesley. Of interest is correspondence with Mark Lesley.
Series VI: Printed Materials. This series is divided into three sub-series of printed materials. A: Works of E. Parker Lesley, Jr.; B: Newspaper Articles; and C: Miscellaneous.
Sub-series A: Works of E. Parker Lesley, Jr. Includes two articles written for Fortune Magazine and "Renaissance Jewels and Jeweled Objects". Of interest is "Renaissance Jewels and Jeweled Objects".
Sub-series B: Newspaper Articles. Includes one article about Lesley, Lesley memoriam and a miscellaneous article.
Sub-series C: Miscellaneous. Includes a book review of "Renaissance Jewels and Jeweled Objects" and miscellaneous reference documents in French and German.
Series VII: Photo Slides. This series is divided into seven sub-series of slides. Sub-series A: Belgium; B: England; C: Israel; D: Massachusetts, U.S.A.; E: Turkey; F: Virginia, U.S.A.; and G: Miscellaneous.
Sub-series A: Belgium.
Sub-series B: England.
Sub-series C: Israel.
Sub-series D: Massachusetts, U.S.A.
Sub-series E: Turkey.
Sub-series F: Virginia, U.S.A.
Sub-series G: Miscellaneous.
Series VIII: Photographs. This series is divided into four sub-series of photographs. A: California, U.S.A.; B: E. Parker Lesley, Jr.; C: Lesley with others; and D: Miscellaneous.
Sub-series A: California, U.S.A. Includes photographs from California trip (photos were collected out of context with California trip documents).
Sub-series B: E. Parker Lesley, Jr. Includes photographs of Lesley dated from 1914 to (1981?).
Sub-series C: Lesley with others. Includes photographs dated from 1914 - 1942.
Sub-series D: Miscellaneous. Includes various photographs of Lesley's parents dated from 1907 - 1938.
Series IX: Miscellaneous. Includes a drawing, postcards, a catalog of works for an exhibit, documents about Gertrude Stein lecture, a memoriam for Lesley and Lesley's mother's recollections about him.
Series X: Negatives.
Series XI: Artifacts. Includes two buttons and five coins.
Contents List
- Series I: Personal
  - Sub-series A: Calendar Planner
    - Calendar Planner, 1974 (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Calendar Planner, 1979 (Box-folder 1:2)
    - Calendar Planner, 1981 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Sub-series B: Pocket notepad
    - Pocket notepad, June 24 - Aug. 15, 1977 (Box-folder 1:4)
    - Pocket notepad, Aug. 22 - April 29, 1978 (Box-folder 1:5)
    - Pocket notepad, May 5 - June 25, 1978 (Box-folder 1:6)
    - Pocket notepad, July 9, 1978 - May 15, 1979 (Box-folder 1:7)
    - Pocket notepad, March 4 - 12, 1979 (Box-folder 1:8)
    - Pocket notepad, Oct. 4 - 20, 1979 (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Sub-series C: Travel log
    - Travel log - Norfolk to Iowa, Aug. - Sept. 1962 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Sub-series D: Works
    - Norfolk Museum of Arts and Sciences' Art-historical handbook 2nd version (copy of original), June 23, 1958 (Box-folder 1:11)
    - "Bibelots" manuscript, Feb. 26, 1979 (Box-folder 1:12)
    - Lecture notes, 1958 - 1962 (?) (Box-folder 1:13)
    - Norfolk Museum of Arts and Sciences' Art-historical handbook 2nd version (original), June 23, 1958 (Box-folder 2:1)
    - "The Iconography of the Spirit" from "Our Lord the Spirit", 1976 (Box-folder 3:1)
    - Painting, date unknown (Box-folder 3:2)
    - Poetry: German to English translation (photos relate to folder document), date unknown (Box-folder 3:3)
    - Typed manuscript, date unknown (Box-folder 3:4)
    - Works cited, date unknown (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Sub-series E: Miscellaneous
    - Birth certificate, July 10, 1929 and July 14, 1939 (Box-folder 3:6)
    - Certificate of Baptism, April 26, 1914 (Box-folder 3:7)
    - Contract letter from Fortune Magazine, June 28, 1955 (Box-folder 3:8)
    - Contract of sale, July 1948 (Box-folder 3:9)
    - Curriculum Vitae (copy), Oct. 7, 1970 (Box-folder 3:10)
    - Grace and Wilson Engel, July 30, 1978 - Jan. 23, 1982 (Box-folder 3:11)
    - Envelope, Feb. 27, 1979 (Box-folder 3:12)
    - Envelope, Nov. 13, 1981 (Box-folder 3:13)
    - Envelope which contained Art-historical handbook, date unknown (Box-folder 3:14)
    - Judgment for divorce, Jan. 26, 1948 (Box-folder 3:15)
    - Miscellaneous addresses, dates unknown (Box-folder 3:16)
    - Porcelain picture of Miriam Pfaff-Lesley, date unknown (Box-folder 3:17)
    - Retirement certificate from Old Dominion University, May 12, 1979 (Box-folder 3:18)
- Series II: Student Records
  - Bachelor of Arts degree, June 18, 1934 (Box-folder 3:19)
  - Certificate from Cours Universitaires de Vacances, Aug. 14, 1937 (Box-folder 3:20)
  - Degree, April 9, 1935 (Box-folder 3:21)
  - High School Diploma, June 13, 1930 (Box-folder 3:22)
  - Letter of Award by Queen of the Netherlands, Dec. 1947 (Box-folder 3:23)
  - Master of Fine Arts degree, June 22, 1937 (Box-folder 3:24)
  - Transcripts, date unknown (Box-folder 3:25)
- Series III: Military Records
  - Award of the Bronze Star Medal Citation (Box-folder 3:26)
  - Certificate of Commendation, date unknown (Box-folder 3:27)
  - Certificate of completion, April 22, 1944 (Box-folder 3:28)
  - Certificate of Proficiency, December 23, 1942 (Box-folder 3:29)
  - Certificate of Service, Nov. 26, 1946 (Box-folder 3:30)
  - Honorable Discharge from QMC OCS, Dec. 23, 1942 (Box-folder 3:31)
  - Honorable Discharge, April 1, 1953 (Box-folder 3:32)
  - Promotion certificate, March 27, 1947 (Box-folder 3:33)
  - Promotion statement, Dec. 23, 1942 (Box-folder 3:34)
  - Promotion statement, April 13, 1943 (Box-folder 3:35)
- Series IV: Correspondence
  - Sub-series A: Amsterdam Trip
    - Amsterdam trip and correspondence, 1974 (Box-folder 4:1)
  - Sub-series B: Brenda Gilchrist
    - Correspondence with Brenda Gilchrist, May 2, 1977 - Feb. 15, 1979 (Box-folder 4:2)
  - Sub-series C: John V. Lesley
    - Correspondence with John V. Lesley, Dec. 19, 1970 - Apr. 30, 1981 (Box-folder 4:3)
  - Sub-series D: Riemann Family
    - Correspondence with the Riemann Family (photos related to correspondence), Sept. 24, 1963 - Nov. 2, 1981 (Box-folder 4:4)
  - Sub-series E: John Roper
    - Correspondence with John Roper, Oct. 16, 1976 - Aug. 23, 1978 (Box-folder 4:5)
  - Sub-series F: Steven Rustari
    - Correspondence with Steven Rustari, Oct. 26, 1972 - June 8, 1980 (Box-folder 4:6)
  - Sub-series G: Miscellaneous
    - Letter of Appointment from National Gallery of Art, July 22, 1974 (Box-folder 4:7)
    - Correspondence from Perry Bottley, July 15, 1977 (Box-folder 4:8)
    - Correspondence with John Carter Brown, May 23, 1978 - Jan. 8, 1980 (Box-folder 4:9)
    - Correspondence with Linda Downs, March 28 - 30, 1978 (Box-folder 4:10)
    - Correspondence to Mr. Farmer, date unknown (Box-folder 4:11)
    - Correspondence to James and Minnie Fosburgh, June 10, 1955 (Box-folder 4:12)
    - Correspondence from Hugh Honour to Ms. Little, April 14, 1978 (Box-folder 4:13)
    - Correspondence Hans and Ellie Jaffe, Jan. 15, 1977 - Sept. 23, 1980 (Box-folder 4:14)
    - Correspondence from Mrs. Horst W. Janson, March 17, 1978 (Box-folder 4:15)
    - Card to E. Parker Lesley, Jr., date unknown (Box-folder 4:16)
    - Correspondence with E. Parker Lesley, Sr., Aug. 9, 1942 - Feb. 23, 1943 (Box-folder 4:17)
    - Correspondence with Mark Lesley, June 23, 1972 (Box-folder 4:18)
    - Correspondence with Mrs. E. Parker Lesley, Sr., Feb. 15, 1945 - Dec. 7, 1954 (Box-folder 4:19)
    - Correspondence from Dr. Joachim Menzhausen, April 19, 1978 (Box-folder 4:20)
    - Letter to New York Times Editor, Oct. 20, 1972 (Box-folder 4:21)
    - Correspondence with Chloe Obolensky, Sept. 25, 1977 - Feb. 2, 1978 (Box-folder 4:22)
    - Correspondence with Charles Parkhurst, March 1978 - May 27, 1982 (Box-folder 4:23)
    - Correspondence to Dr. Jay Pawa, April 21, 1978 (Box-folder 4:24)
    - Letters to Her Majesty the Queen of the Netherlands, Feb. 21, 1980 (Box-folder 4:25)
    - Letters regarding "Renaissance Jewels and Jeweled Objects", Sept. 24, 1968 - Feb. 20, 1970 (Box-folder 4:26)
    - Correspondence to Mr. Rohlfing, June 15, 1978 (Box-folder 4:27)
    - Correspondence with Dale Rothman, Jan. 18 - Feb. 19, 1980 (Box-folder 4:28)
    - Letter of congratulations from Charles Sibley, May 16, 1967 (Box-folder 4:29)
    - Correspondence from Marilyn P. Swezey, May 20, 1978 (Box-folder 4:30)
    - Correspondence from Lisa Taylor to Philippe de Montebello, Feb. 21, 1978 (Box-folder 4:31)
    - Correspondence to unknown person, Nov. 7, 1981 (Box-folder 4:32)
    - Letter to the Editor of the Virginian-Pilot, Jan. 14, 1966 (Box-folder 4:33)
    - Correspondence with Herbie Weissburger, Oct. 27, 1970 - Nov. 11, 1973 (Box-folder 4:34)
- Series V: Trips
  - Sub-series A: California, U.S.A.
    - "5,000 Years of Korean Art" brochure, May 1 - Sept. 30, 1979 (Box-folder 5:1)
    - Map of California, 1974 (Box-folder 5:2)
    - Map of San Francisco, 1969 (Box-folder 5:3)
    - Car and Truck Renting and Leasing Assoc. (CATRALA) newsletter, May 1979 (Box-folder 5:4)
    - Car rental paperwork, Sept. 11 - Oct. 2, 1979 (Box-folder 5:5)
    - Plane ticket, Sept. 11 - Oct. 2, 1979 (Box-folder 5:6)
    - Pocket notepad, Sept. 11 - Oct. 2, 1979 (Box-folder 5:7)
    - Postcards, Sept. 11 - Oct. 2, 1979 (Box-folder 5:8)
  - Sub-series B: Russia
    - Check-in card, Kosmos Hotel, Oct. 16 - 20, 1981 (Box-folder 5:9)
    - Check-in card, Pribaltiyskaya Hotel, Oct. 22 - 25, 1981 (Box-folder 5:10)
    - Correspondence from Mayree Fourman, Nov. 4, 1981 - March 3, 1982 (Box-folder 5:11)
    - "Do not disturb" sign, Pribaltiyskaya Hotel, Oct. 22 - 25, 1981 (Box-folder 5:12)
    - Flight itinerary, Oct. 15 - 25, 1981 (Box-folder 5:13)
    - Information pamphlet, Oct. 22 - 25, 1981 (Box-folder 5:14)
    - Luggage nametag, Oct. 15 - 25, 1981 (Box-folder 5:15)
    - Map of Moscow and Leningrad, date unknown (Box-folder 5:16)
    - Miscellaneous theater tickets, Oct. 15 - 25, 1981 (Box-folder 5:17)
    - General Tours paperwork, Oct. 15 - 25, 1981 (Box-folder 5:18)
    - Plane tickets, Oct. 15 - 25, 1981 (Box-folder 5:19)
    - Receipt for one admission ticket, Hermitage Museum, Oct. 23, 1981 (Box-folder 5:20)
    - Receipt for one admission ticket, Russia Museum, Oct. 24, 1981 (Box-folder 5:21)
    - Receipt for one admission ticket "Special Exhibit", Russia Museum, Oct. 24, 1981 (Box-folder 5:22)
    - Receipt for ticket service, Oct. 24, 1981 (Box-folder 5:23)
    - Theatre Review 1, Oct. 15 - 25, 1981 (Box-folder 5:24)
    - Theatre Review 2, Oct. 15 - 25, 1981 (Box-folder 5:25)
    - Travel Voucher, Oct. 15 - 25, 1981 (Box-folder 5:26)
    - Writing paper, Oct. 22 - 25, 1981 (Box-folder 5:27)
  - Sub-series C: Seattle, Washington, U.S.A.
    - Map of Seattle, July 27, 1981 (Box-folder 5:28)
    - Map of Seattle Tour, 1981 (Box-folder 5:29)
    - "The Ring" newspaper review, 1981 (Box-folder 5:30)
    - Postcards, 1981 (Box-folder 5:31)
    - "The Ring" program, July 18 - Aug. 2, 1981 (Box-folder 5:32)
    - "Roy Lichtenstein 1970 - 1980", July 30, 1981 (Box-folder 5:33)
    - Ticket stubs, July 28 and Aug. 2, 1981 (Box-folder 5:34)
    - Tour group photograph, 1981 (Box-folder 5:35)
    - Tour membership certificate, July 27 - Aug. 4, 1981 (Box-folder 5:36)
    - Tour program outline, July 28 - Aug. 4, 1981 (Box-folder 5:37)
  - Sub-series D: Taiwan, Thailand, India and Nepal
    - "Bali", 1977 (Box-folder 5:38)
    - Blank envelope, Sept. 5 - Nov. 5, 1980 (Box-folder 5:39)
    - Certification of visit, Mt. Everest, Oct. 27, 1980 (Box-folder 5:40)
    - Correspondence with Doris Kurth, March 21 - Apr. 6, 1981 (Box-folder 5:41)
    - Diary and notes, Sept. 5 - Oct. 7, 1980 (Box-folder 6:1)
    - Tour group photograph, Taj Mahal, 1980 (Box-folder 6:2)
    - "Guide to Taiwan: Republic of China", 1977 (Box-folder 6:3)
    - "Guide to the Grand Palace", Thailand, date unknown (Box-folder 6:4)
    - Invoice, Moore Travel, Inc., Aug. 5, 1980 (Box-folder 6:5)
    - "The Development of Porcelain" literature, Sept. 11, 1980 (Box-folder 6:6)
    - "The Development of Pottery" literature, Sept. 11, 1980 (Box-folder 6:7)
    - "Exhibit of Miniature Treasures and Treasure-Boxes" literature, Sept. 11, 1980 (Box-folder 6:8)
    - "Mastery in Carving" literature, Sept. 11, 1980 (Box-folder 6:9)
    - "My Country", Taiwan, Feb. 1980 (Box-folder 6:10)
    - "The Ritual Vessels of Ancient China" literature, Sept. 11, 1980 (Box-folder 6:11)
    - Nepal brochure, June 1979 (Box-folder 6:12)
    - "Orientation to the National Palace Museum Collection and It's Historical Background" literature, Sept. 11, 1980 (Box-folder 6:13)
    - Photograph, Thailand, Sept. 22, 1980 (Box-folder 6:14)
    - Plane tickets, Sept. 5 - Nov. 5, 1980 (Box-folder 6:15)
    - Purchases, Sept. 25 - Oct. 28, 1980 (Box-folder 6:16)
    - Receipts, Indian Airlines, Oct. 28 - 29, 1980 (Box-folder 6:17)
    - Receipt, Taj Mahal Hotel, Nov. 2, 1980 (Box-folder 6:18)
    - Daily Mountain Flight, Royal Nepal Airlines, date unknown (Box-folder 6:19)
    - Schedule and itinerary, Sept. 5 - Nov. 5, 1980 (Box-folder 6:20)
    - "Thailand", date unknown (Box-folder 6:21)
    - Tour program outline and itinerary, Oct. 10 - Nov. 5, 1980 (Box-folder 6:22)
    - Travel insurance, Sept. 3, 1980 (Box-folder 6:23)
  - Sub-series E: Turkey
    - Class information, May 11, 1970 (Box-folder 6:24)
    - Correspondence to Mark Lesley, July 27 - Aug. 7, 1970 (Box-folder 6:25)
    - Itinerary and syllabus, July 1970 (Box-folder 6:26)
    - List of participants, July 1970 (Box-folder 6:27)
    - Plan of Miletus, July 1970 (Box-folder 6:28)
    - Plan of Selge, July 1970 (Box-folder 6:29)
    - Site information, July 1970 (Box-folder 6:30)
- Series VI: Printed Materials
  - Sub-series A: Works of E. Parker Lesley, Jr.
    - Fortune Magazine, Dec. 1955 (Box-folder 6:31)
    - Fortune Magazine, Jan. 1956 (Box-folder 6:32)
    - "Renaissance Jewels and Jeweled Objects", 1968 (Box-folder 6:33)
  - Sub-series B: Newspaper Articles
    - "Art: A strategy for viewing the Whitney Biennial", Feb. 6, 1981 (Box-folder 7:1)